LALA RUKH

07462550951 • lalarukh.1992@outlook.com • www.linkedin.com/in/lala-rukh-9019a6144/ • https://github.com/lalarukh1

Summary:

As a dedicated software developer specializing in front-end development with a passion for UX/UI design, I consistently deliver top-tier results by following best practices and industry standards. Hard work and determination are my key qualities and I thrive on continuous self-learning. My goal is to blend technical proficiency with creative design to produce inclusive, efficient and delightful user experiences.

Work Experience:

The Access Group, Loughborough (GCSEPod) as Software Developer

Jan 2020 - Present.

- Dedicated 5 years to crafting immersive user experiences while delivering several projects aimed for teachers and students with the help of React with Typescript and Vue.js frameworks.
- Mastered Tailwind CSS and Bootstrap to create visually appealing and responsive designs, enhancing user engagement.
- Established and maintained coding standards, ensuring clean and maintainable codebases across projects.
- Increased site performance and reduced site build times significantly by migrating the site from Webpack 4 to Webpack 5 successfully.
- Leveraged Figma to design intuitive user interfaces that elevate user interactions and streamline workflows. Conducted user research and usability testing to gather feedback and iterate on UX design solutions.
- Developed AI Co-Pilot plugins while gaining proficiency with GPT-3 and GPT-4 models, alongside mastering prompt engineering techniques.
- Implemented and ensured compliance with WCAG accessibility standards, led accessibility initiatives by implementing and refining rules within existing systems to enhance usability for screen readers.
- Guided junior developers in adapting web development best practices, fostering their growth and skills and a culture of collaboration within the team.
- Played a pivotal role in work planning meetings, scrums, and consistently ensured on-time project delivery throughout my tenure.
- Completed a personal project to get hands-on experience in building and consuming RESTful APIs, utilizing Postman for testing and documentation, using Express.js and Node.js for server-side development, integrating MongoDB with Mongoose for data management and using React for frontend.

Hays Travel, Head office Sunderland as Junior Web Developer

Nov 2018 – Jan 2020.

- Played an integral role in delivering the re-development of Hays Cruise website and CMS projects successfully.
- Trained and mentored an intern to proficiently utilize technologies used by the company.
- Developed a new system for the careers team and delivered the essential training successfully.

Hays Travel, Head Office Sunderland as Graduate Web Developer

Mar 2018 - Nov 2018.

- Received training and mentorship to get up to speed with the existing system and technologies.
- Worked on several projects such as redevelopment of Hays Faraway CMS while learning the new technologies.
- Provided technical support for updating the existing web platforms for the company as per requests from different departments on a day-to-day basis.

Bede Gaming, Newcastle upon Tyne as Technology Intern

Feb 2018 – Mar 2018.

- Gained an insight into Company operations and gambling platform industry.
- Developed technical and communication skills and applied knowledge practically within the workplace.
- Worked on a JavaScript based project using company's SPINE API for extracting player data.

Education:

Northumbria University, Newcastle Upon Tyne, UK – (Distinction)

Jan 2018.

Masters in computing and IT (Advanced Practice) | 80.5%.

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science | 3.26 GPA

Technical Skills:

Vue.js, React.js, Typescript, Tailwind, Bootstrap, CSS, HTML5, JavaScript, Figma, Git, Postman.

Voluntary Experience:

- 1. Northumbria University, Newcastle upon Tyne as Class Representative. January 2017 December 2017.
- 2. NFC Blood Donor Society, NFC Institute of Engineering and Fertilizer Research, Pakistan as **in-charge Management**. November 2012 September 2013.
- 3. NFC Blood Donor Society, NFC Institute of Engineering and Fertilizer Research, Pakistan as **Computer Science Representative**. November 2011- October 2012.
- 4. NFC Blood Donor Society (BDS), NFC Institute of Engineering and Fertilizer Research, Pakistan as **In-charge Arts and Display Wing**. November 2010 October 2011.
- 5. NFC Association for Computing Machinery (ACM) Society, NFC Institute of Engineering, Pakistan as **Hostel Representative**. February 2012 March 2013.

Achievements:

- The Access Group Hackathon winner for 2023 and 2024.
- IELTS academic Test BAND 7.5

Interests

- · Painting, Squash, Working out.
- Exploring and discovering new places.

References are available on request.